Inventory of the George Smith Papers 1871-1954
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
George Smith Papers 1871-1954
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 1972.46
0.70
This collection details the personal and professional papers of George Smith and William E. Nelson. Legal documents consist of deeds, forms, and official papers. Business materials include account books, checks, and promissory notes. The collection also covers various publications and a few personal correspondences.
Smith, George, Born before 1855 and died after 1940.; Nelson, William E., 1880 - arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 09/01/1972.
Biographical Note
George Smith lived in New Plymouth, Lunenburg County, Virginia during the late 1800's to mid 1900's. Possibly a lawyer who mostly handled land transactions.
Scope and Contents
This collection details the personal and professional papers of George Smith and William E. Nelson. Legal documents consist of deeds, forms, and official papers. Business materials include account books, checks, and promissory notes. The collection also covers various publications and a few personal correspondences.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is arranged into three series. Series one details the legal and personal papers of George Smith. Series two covers papers from the law practice of William E. Nelson. Series Three consists of legal documents and various publications.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Account books; Correspondence; Deeds; Legal documents; Publications
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: George Smith
- George Smith, 1871-1949
  Legal papers of George Smith with a few personal papers and letters. Legal papers mostly concern land transactions, but also include client credit records and personal account information.
  - Letters to George and Mrs. Smith, 1871-1879 (1)
  - Letters to George and Mrs. Smith, 1881-1910 (2)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1880-1899 (3)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1900-1909 (4)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1910-1919 (5)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1920-1929 (6)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1930-1942 (7)
  - Deeds and Legal Papers, 1943-1949 (8)
  - Legal Papers n.d. and misc. (9)
  Series 2: William E. Nelson
- William E. Nelson, 1908-1954
  Papers from the law practice of William E. Nelson of Lunenburg County. Includes correspondence, legal documents, client forms from the Bureau of Credit, credit reports, other legal material regarding cases and publications of the Commonwealth of Virginia on taxation, finance and other related subjects.
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1908-1917 (10)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (11)
  - Legal Forms, Correspondences, and Credit Reports, 1910 (12)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (13)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (14)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1903-1910 (15)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910-1954 (16)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (17)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (18)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (19)
  - Legal Forms and Correspondences, 1910 (20)
  Series 3: Financial-Legal Documents and Journal
- Financial-Legal Documents and Journal, 1862-1940
  - Business Accounts, 1889-1901 (21)
  - Checks and Promissory Notes, 1897-1944 (22)
    Checks- George Smith 1897-1916, Alice Smith 1944 / Promissory Notes- 1918- 1930
  - Printed Material and Farm Journal, 1884-1940 (23)
    Farm journal refers to "Farm and Home," a semi-monthly periodical published by Phelps Publishing Co. concerning agricultural and farming matters.
  - Business Accounts, 1869-1871 (24)
    Accounts of George Smith with Devon Cornwall Banking Co.
  - Bank Book, 1888-1897 (25)
    George Smith bank book
  - Account Book, 1862-1876 (26)
    George Smith account book 1862-1870 (main part) 1874 and 1876 (fragments)
  - Instructional Math Book, 1895-1898 (27)
    Handwritten math instructional material followed by accounts in the back.
  - Account Book, 1892-1941 (28)
    Account book 1892-1893 (fragments) 1916-1939 (main part) 1940-1941 (fragments)
  - Account Book, 1903-1908 (29)
    Account Book 1906-1908 (main part) 1903-1905 (fragments)
  - File Cabinet (30)
    File cabinet instructions and components